Rahul Chauhan

crahul10101991@gmail.com | 8460870595

Summary

Current working as a Senior Software Engineer in UK based company PMC retail. 5+ years' experience specializing in backend services and web application development. Proficient in development, execution and maintenance of coding of the application. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience

Paul Mason Consulting Pvt Ltd.

Dec. 2018 – Present Vadodara, Gujarat

Travel Cat - Contact Center Application - National Express Group

- Added new features in user management module managing permissions for 500 contact center persons.
- Development of new features in existing micro services, responsible to resolve issues in existing application.

ESB – Coach Site - National Express Group

- Working as a backend engineer, developing and supporting backend services for National Express UK
- Implemented historical data extraction process for business intelligence team.

Eclinicalworks India Pvt Ltd.

Nov. 2017 - Dec. 2018 Ahmedabad, Gujarat

110 - Electronic Health Record System

- Worked as application developer in Admission-Discharge-Transfer module.
- Developed an easy-to-use, configuration setup for patient transfers in inpatient facilities.
- Wrote test cases using Spock framework from scratch covering 99% of module code.

Gridscape Solutions

Apr. 2016 – Nov. 2017 Vadodara, Gujarat

Energy-Scope – Energy Flow Management Application

- Created unified dashboard displaying energy flow from grid, solar to fire-station using Highcharts.
- Enabled predictive choice of energy source using Schneider energy APIs.
- Developed new features as part of business requirements funded by US government.

HECO – Instructions for Distributed Energy Resources - Green Charge Networks

- Designed and developed scheduler application using quartz to send 1L of instructions to DER.
- Designed fault tolerant scheduling windows which handles errors gracefully.

ABB EVSE Payment Library - ABB Group

- Converted C++ library into Java library. Used RxTx for serial communication.
- Added simultaneous transaction feature. Added test cases to cover ABB scenarios.

Neetai Tech

Aug. 2015 – Apr. 2016 Vadodara, Gujarat

School ERP

- Developed electronic fee receipt module using ITEXT library.
- Added new term feature to shift students from current term to next term.
- Responsible for solving issues in existing application and find possible solution.

VIVID - Equipment Management

- Responsible for working on outstanding issues raised by client.
- Developed e-receipt module using ITEXT.
- Re-design invoice module to accommodate latest feature information.

Languages & Technologies

Java, Struts, Spring, WebMethod, CouchDB, MSSql

Education

Parul Institute of Engineering and Technology – Master of Engineering in Computer

Aug. 2013 - April. 2015

Gujarat Institute of Technical Studies – Bachelor of Engineering in Computer